Ellen L. Lutz Papers MS177
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Research materials and field investigations regarding victims of the military juntas in Uruguay, Argentina and Chile, 1960 -- 1986; 1976 -- 1985; MS177.002; 2.95 Linear Feet; 1 Audiovisual Object(s); 5 Digital Object(s)
  - [Maps and contacts], 1984; MS177.002.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Uruguay: 10/79 UACHR finding, 1979; MS177.002.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - ICRC Mission Report: Uruguay, 1980, MS177.002.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - OAS Report - Uruguay 1978, MS177.002.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Uruguay: Grupo de Convergencia, 1980 -- 1981; MS177.002.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Uruguay: Institutional Acts, 1979; MS177.002.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - [Letter to Margo Picken regarding upcoming travel in Argentine, Chile and Uruguay], 1985; MS177.002.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - [Passport photographs], 1985; MS177.002.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - My appreciations are [numbered outline], 1985; MS177.002.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - [Notebooks of work notes and contacts], 1985; MS177.002.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - [Two children's paintings], 1985; MS177.002.002.00020 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
    This date is approximate. Items are oversize; folder is located in map case.
  - Niños Desaparecidos: Su Restitución, 1984; MS177.002.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - [Argentina contacts and correspondence], 1985; MS177.002.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - Todavía Cantamos [song by Víctor Heredia, sung by Mercedes Soros], 1985; MS177.002.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - 'The Trial of the Argentine Generals' (11/85 - published in AI Legal Support Newsletter), 1985; MS177.002.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - [Newspaper clippings regarding trial of Argentine generals], 1983 -- 1985; MS177.002.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - [Argentina Senate revision of articles 1-16], 1985; MS177.002.002.00026 (Box MS177 Shared 2)
    Located separately in legal-sized box.
  - Analysis del Ritual Juridico: 'El Proceso Judicial a los Ex Comandantes de las Juntas Militares', 1985; MS177.002.002.00027 (Box MS177 Shared 2)
  - Marcelo Parrilli - CELS, atty. 8/21/85 (B.A.), 1985-08-21; MS177.002.002.00028 (Case 2)
    In Spanish. Located separately in brown barcodes.
    audiocassette
  - Ester Kaufman 8/21/85 (Buenos Aires), 1985-08-21; MS177.002.002.00029 (Case 2)
  - [Contacts, notes and a map of Santiago], 1985; MS177.002.002.00030 (Box 2)
  - [Report regarding May 1985 conference, 'La Cultura del Miedo en los Regimenes Militares del Cono Sur,' in Buenos Aires, Argentina], MS177.002.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - [Newspaper clippings regarding Argentine generals trial and photographs of Ellen Lutz and Glenn Randall], 1985; MS177.002.002.00032 (Box 2)
    - [Man in a green sweater talks to people outdoors], 1985; MS177.002.002.00032.00001; Unknown (Box 2)
      Randall, Glenn R.; Lutz, Ellen L.
    - [Glenn Randall sitting on a couch], 1985; MS177.002.002.00032.00002; Unknown (Box 2)
      Randall, Glenn R.
    - [Glenn Randall and Ellen Lutz at an outdoor meal], 1985; MS177.002.002.00032.00003; Unknown (Box 2)
      Picnics; Dinners and Dining; Randall, Glenn R.; Lutz, Ellen L.
  - [Eric Stover, et al. correspondence regarding Argentina contacts], 1985; MS177.002.002.00033 (Box MS177 Shared 2)
    Located separately in legal-size box.
  - Ley de Amnistia [resolution of Juez Penal de Sentencia], 1983; MS177.002.002.00034 (Box 2)
  - [Centro de Estudios Legales y Sociales bulletins and related material], 1984 -- 1985; MS177.002.002.00035 (Box MS177 Shared 2)
  - [Fragment regarding Javier Velázquez, by Carlos M. Britos Huertas], 1985; MS177.002.002.00036 (Box MS177 Shared 2)
  - Las Bases, 1985; MS177.002.002.00037 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
    Items are oversize; folder is located in map case.
  - La Hora, 1985; MS177.002.002.00038 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
    Item is oversize; folder is located in map case.
  - Escritos Sobre Exilio y Retorno (1978-1984), MS177.002.002.00039; Fundacion de Ayuda Social de las Iglesias Cristianas (Box 2)
  - Lecturas de Psicológia y Politica: Crisis Politica y Daño Psicológico, Tomo II, 1983; MS177.002.002.00040; Colectivo Chileno de Trabajo Psicosocial (Box 2)
  - Así se Tortura en Chile, 1984; MS177.002.002.00041; Comision Nacional contra la Tortura (Chile) (Box 2)
  - Informe Mensual: Situacion de los Derechos Humanos en Chile, 1985-05-01 -- 1985-06-01; MS177.002.002.00042; Comision Chilena de Derechos Humanos (Box 2)
  - Yumbel: Cuando los Muertos Vuelvan a su Tierra, 1979; MS177.002.002.00043; Fundacion de Ayuda Social de las Iglesias Cristianas (Box 2)
  - Artesanias: Una Red de Amor, Dignidad y Esperanza, 1985; MS177.002.002.00044; Vicaria de la Solidaridad. Arzobispado de Santiago (Box 2)
  - Solidaridad ante Situaciones de Amedrentamiento, 1985; MS177.002.002.00045; Vicaria de la Solidaridad. Arzobispado de Santiago (Box 2)
  - Por la Vida y la Justicia, no. 9, 1985-08-01; MS177.002.002.00046; Agrupacion de familiares de Ejecutados Politicos de Chile (Box 2)
  - Premio Colegio de Psicologos 1983, Psicologia y Derechos Humanos, MS177.002.002.00047; Fundacion de Ayuda Social de las Iglesias Cristianas (Box 2)
  - Textos Comparados de la Constitucion Politica de la Republica de Chile y de la Constitucion Politica de la Republica de Chile de 1925, 1980-08-28; MS177.002.002.00048 (Box 2)
  - La Vicaria de la Solidaridad, 1985; MS177.002.002.00049; Vicaria de la Solidaridad. Arzobispado de Santiago (Box 2)
  - Reproduccion y Socilazio de Nucleos de Resistencia: La Experiencia de la Vicaria de la Solidaridad en Chile, 1985; MS177.002.002.00050; Frühling, Hugo (Box 2)
  - Todo Chile Relegado, no. 7, 1985-07-01; MS177.002.002.00051; Agrupacion de Familiares de Relegados y Ex-Relegados (Box 2)
  - Mario Fernández López (Otro Amparo Rechazado), Tortura y Muerta en Chile, 1984-12-01; MS177.002.002.00052; Comision Nacional contra la Tortura (Chile) (Box 2)
  - ¡ Hasta Cuando se Tortura en Chile! Carlos Godoy Echegoyen, un Nuevo Caso de Detenido Muerto en Torturaas, 1985-08-01; MS177.002.002.00053; Comision Nacional contra la Tortura (Chile) (Box 2)
  - [Pamphlets from Chile], 1985; MS177.002.002.00054 (Box 2)
  - Vida Médica, vol. 36, no. 1: La Salud Pública en Chile 1985, MS177.002.002.00055; Colegio Médico de Chile (Box 2)
  - Resumen de Prensa, 1985-07-01; MS177.002.002.00056; Vicaria de la Solidaridad. Arzobispado de Santiago (Box 2)
  - Human Rights and Mental Health in Chile, 1985; MS177.002.002.00057; Mercer, Ellen Robertson (Box 2)
  - Human Rights in Chile: The Role of the Medical Profession, 1986-07-01; MS177.002.002.00058; Amnesty International (Box 2)
  - Vicaria de la Solidaridad: Noveno Año de Labor, 1984, MS177.002.002.00059; Vicaria de la Solidaridad. Arzobispado de Santiago (Box MS177 Shared 2)
  - Vicaria de la Solidaridad: Octavo Año de Labor, 1983, MS177.002.002.00060; Vicaria de la Solidaridad. Arzobispado de Santiago (Box MS177 Shared 2)
  - Informe Mensual, 1985; MS177.002.002.00061; Vicaria de la Solidaridad. Arzobispado de Santiago (Box MS177 Shared 2)
  - Solidaridad: Compromiso con la Verdad, 1985; MS177.002.002.00062 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
  - Cosas, no. 233, 1985-09-05; MS177.002.002.00063 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
  - [Tacora indices], 1985; MS177.002.002.00064 (Box MS177 Shared 2)
  - [Newspaper clippings regarding José Cánovas and CIA behavior control], 1977 -- 1985; MS177.002.002.00065 (Box MS177 Shared 2)
  - [Colegio Medico de Chile documents], 1984; MS177.002.002.00066 (Box MS177 Shared 2)
  - La Razon, 1985; MS177.002.002.00067 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
  - El Diario de Juicio, 1985; MS177.002.002.00068 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
  - El Diario de Juicio, 1985; MS177.002.002.00069 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
  - El Diario de Juicio, 1985; MS177.002.002.00070 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
  - El Diario de Juicio, 1985; MS177.002.002.00071 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
  - El Diario de Juicio, 1985; MS177.002.002.00072 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
  - El Diario de Juicio, 1985; MS177.002.002.00073 (Box Large Map Case 2 Drawer 3)
- Human Rights Watch and American Civil Liberties Union files, 1979 -- 1998; 1989 -- 1994; MS177.003; 3.6 Linear Feet
  This series contains presentations, notes, reports, testimony and correspondence. The bulk of the material dates from 1989 to 1994, when Lutz worked as the California Director for Human Rights Watch. Most of the series consists of Human Rights Watch testimony and correspondence regarding the US ratification of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights and the US ratification of the Torture Convention. Also included are reports from 1991 to 1992 regarding policy brutality and the Los Angeles Police Department in the aftermath of the abuse of Rodney King.
  - [Indigenous rights and democracy in Mexico], 1989 -- 1992; MS177.003.011.00021 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Draft testimony re: US ratification of torture con., 1984 -- 1989; MS177.003.011.00022 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [10 Deadly Deposition Sins], 1985; MS177.003.011.00023 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - EL: Talks about human rights (L.A.), 1988; MS177.003.011.00024 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [Articles and reports regarding human rights], 1988 -- 1993; MS177.003.011.00025 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [US ratification of the convention against torture, testimony and op-ed], 1989; MS177.003.011.00026 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [Convention against torture], 1989 -- 1990; MS177.003.011.00027 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - The U.S. Constitution and International Human Rights Law - Richard Lillich, 1990; MS177.003.011.00028 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Testimony re: civil and political covenant 12/91: 1992 debate re: ratification of HR covenants, 1991 -- 1992; MS177.003.011.00029 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Testimony re: civil and political covenant 12/91 [1 of 3], 1991; MS177.003.011.00030 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Testimony re: civil and political covenant 12/91 [2 of 3], 1991; MS177.003.011.00031 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Testimony re: civil and political covenant 12/91 [3 of 3], 1991; MS177.003.011.00032 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [Trajano v. Marcos, brief of Human Rights Watch as amicus curiae], 1991; MS177.003.011.00033 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - US prison visits - 1991, MS177.003.011.00034 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [Americas Watch newsletters and reports], 1991 -- 1994; MS177.003.011.00035 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Staff retreat, 1992; MS177.003.011.00036 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [Correspondence regarding US ratification of international covenant on civil and political rights], 1992; MS177.003.011.00037 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Speech to Santa Monica Unitarian Universalist Church, 12/92, 1992; MS177.003.011.00038 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [Mexican newspaper and notes], 1992; MS177.003.011.00039 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [Haitian Centers Council v. McNary, brief amicus curiae of Americas Watch], 1992; MS177.003.011.00040 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - HR Watch dinner speech, 1992, MS177.003.011.00041 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [Mexico notes and drafts], 1992 -- 1993; MS177.003.011.00042 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Political rights vs. economic rights, 1992 -- 1994; MS177.003.011.00043 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - UC San Diego presentation, 2/17/93, 1993; MS177.003.011.00044 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Loyola conference on Mexican elections - 2/20, 1993; MS177.003.011.00045 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Border trip, 3/18-19/93, MS177.003.011.00046 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Treaty ratification letter, 4/93, 1993; MS177.003.011.00047 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Accountability panel - Whittier College confrence - 6/93, 1993; MS177.003.011.00048 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - David Mason execution speech, 1993; MS177.003.011.00049 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Emily Levine event EL speech, 1993; MS177.003.011.00050 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Legal standards for prevention and treatment of torture - APHS conference 20/93, 1993; MS177.003.011.00051 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Op-ed re: Mexico post NAFTA, 1993; MS177.003.011.00052 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Schroeder bill on female circumcision, 1993; MS177.003.011.00053 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Inter-American dialogue conference, 1993; MS177.003.011.00054 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - HRW dinner speech - 1993, MS177.003.011.00055 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - Whittier College of Law speech re: HR in US courts, Marcos - was justice done?, 1993; MS177.003.011.00056 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [Peace agreements in El Salvador and Nicaragua], 1993; MS177.003.011.00057 (Box MS177 Shared 5)
  - [Saudi Arabia, King Faisal Specialist Hospital and Royspec v. Scott Nelson and Vivian Nelson, motion and brief], 1992; MS177.003.020.00001 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - HCC v. McNary, no. 92-6090: HCC v. INS, Americas Watch amicus curiae, 1992; MS177.003.020.00002 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - HCC v. McNary, no. 92-6090: Supreme Court: Haitian Case [1 of 2], 1991 -- 1992; MS177.003.020.00003 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - HCC v. McNary, no. 92-6090: Supreme Court: Haitian Case [2 of 2], 1992; MS177.003.020.00004 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - HCC v. McNary, no. 92-6090: Decision, 2nd Circuit, 1992; MS177.003.020.00005 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - HCC v. McNary, no. 92-6090: Haitian refugee amicus brief, 4/92, 1992; MS177.003.020.00006 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - HR abuses in former Yugoslavia, 1993; MS177.003.020.00007 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - Bosnia-Herzegovina v. Yugoslavia World Court case: genocide, 1993 -- 1995; MS177.003.020.00008 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - Aryeh's testimony re: Bosnia, 2/18/93, 1993; MS177.003.020.00009 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - Bosnia-Herzegovina: Rape and Sexual Abuse by Armed Forces, 1993-01; MS177.003.020.00010; Amnesty International (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - Helsinki Watch - Re: former Yugoslavia, 1991 -- 1993; MS177.003.020.00011 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - [Sanchez-Trujillo and Escobar-Nieto v. Immigration and Naturalization Service, ACLU petition application and brief], 1986; MS177.003.020.00012 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - Corado-Rodriguez v. INS (El Rescate case), 1985; MS177.003.020.00013 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - Presentation to Jewish Comm. Ctr - Long Beach, 5/21/86, 1986; MS177.003.020.00014 (Box MS177 Shared 6)
  - Derechos Humanos en Mexico: Una Politica de Impunidad?, 1991; MS177.003.043.00011; Americas Watch Committee (U.S.) (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - Human Rights Violations in the United States, 1993; MS177.003.043.00012; Human Rights Watch (Organization); American Civil Liberties Union (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - Pelican Bay [1 of 2], 1993; MS177.003.043.00013 (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - Pelican Bay [2 of 2], 1993; MS177.003.043.00014 (Box MS177 Shared 3)
  - United States frontier injustice, 1993; MS177.003.047.00020 (Box MS177 Shared 4)
  - ACLU International Civil Liberties Report, 1998-05; MS177.003.047.00021 (Box MS177 Shared 4)
  - Comments to the United Nations Human Rights Committee Concerning the First Periodic Report of the United States on Compliance with the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, 1995-03; MS177.003.048.00001 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Proposal for a Commission of Inquiry into the Effect of Domestic Intelligence Activities on Criminal Trials in the United States of America, 1981; MS177.003.048.00002 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Amnesty International, USA: Report on Los Angeles Police Department, 1992; MS177.003.048.00003 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Los Angeles Police Department status report of independent commission, 1992; MS177.003.048.00004 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Rodney King / Police Abuse, 1992; MS177.003.048.00005 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - On the Line: Police Brutality and Its Remedies, 1991-04; MS177.003.048.00006 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Report of the Eighth United Nations Congress on Prevention of Crime and Treatment of Offenders, 1990; MS177.003.048.00007 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - United Nations basic principles on use of force and firearms by law enforcement officials, A/Conf. 144/27, 1992; MS177.003.048.00008 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Code of conduct for law enforcement officials, GA res 34/169, 1979; MS177.003.048.00009 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Police brutality - U.S., 1991; MS177.003.048.00010 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Chevigny, 'Let's Make It a Federal Case,' The Nation, 1992; MS177.003.048.00011 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Correspondence and reports regarding police brutality, 1991 -- 1993; MS177.003.048.00012 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Training analysis of the Los Angeles Police Department, 1991; MS177.003.048.00013 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Notes from 'Police Misconduct Litigation: Recent Developments', 1995; MS177.003.048.00014 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - The Call for Change Goes Unanswered, 1992-03; MS177.003.048.00015 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - Civil Liberties in Crisis: Los Angeles During the Emergency, 1992-06-23; MS177.003.048.00016 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - To Rebuild Is Not Enough: Final Report and Recommendations of the Assembly Special Committee on the Los Angeles Crisis, 1992-09-28; MS177.003.048.00017 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - INS Misconduct: Rights and Remedies in Immigration Law Enforcement 1 of 2, 1991; MS177.003.048.00018 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
  - INS Misconduct: Rights and Remedies in Immigration Law Enforcement 2 of 2, 1991; MS177.003.048.00019 (Box MS177 Shared 7)
- Human rights litigation files, 1957 -- 2004; 1986 -- 1999; MS177.004; 17.35 Linear Feet
  This series contains complaints, pleadings and motions, amicus curiae briefs, declarations, depositions, judgments, and appeals, as well as material regarding settlement and damages, dating from 1986 to 1999. The material documents human rights litigation in suits brought against the estate of the former President of the Philippines, Ferdinand Marcos, and against the Argentine general, Carlos Guillermo Suárez-Mason, as well as some files from Supreme Court case, U.S. v. Alvarez-Machain. Lutz represented clients in both the Marcos and Suarez-Mason cases, and the material covering these cases include working notes and drafts of testimony and briefs.
  The series is organized into three subseries: Humberto Alvarez Machain; Ferdinand Marcos [RESTRICTED]; and Carlos Guillermo Suarez Mason.
  - Humberto Alvarez Machain, 1990 -- 2004; 1990 -- 1991; MS177.004.001; 2.4 Linear Feet
    - Alvarez Machain: Oral argument, 9th Circuit (4/4/90), 1990; MS177.004.001.027.00001 (Box 27)
    - Opinion and order of District Court 8/90, 1990; MS177.004.001.027.00002 (Box 27)
    - 6th superseding grand jury indictment, 1990; MS177.004.001.027.00003 (Box 27)
    - Transcripts of hearings before US District Judge Rafeedie (sp. 1990), MS177.004.001.027.00004 (Box 27)
    - US v. Caro Quintero, et al. - District Court decision in Alvarez Machain, 1990; MS177.004.001.027.00005 (Box 27)
    - [9th Circuit court appeal, supplemental excerpts of record], 1990; MS177.004.001.027.00006 (Box 27)
    - Mexico's intervention before 9th Circuit, 1990; MS177.004.001.027.00007 (Box 27)
    - Briefs filed by parties before District Court [1 of 2], 1990; MS177.004.001.027.00008 (Box 27)
    - Briefs filed by parties before District Court [2 of 2], 1990; MS177.004.001.027.00009 (Box 27)
    - Alvarez Machain 9th Circuit - other amicus curiae briefs [1 of 2], 1990; MS177.004.001.027.00010 (Box 27)
    - Alvarez Machain 9th Circuit - other amicus curiae briefs [2 of 2], 1990; MS177.004.001.027.00011 (Box 27)
    - Declarations of witnesses to Alvarez Machain's arrest, 1990; MS177.004.001.027.00012 (Box 27)
    - District Court proceedings - Alvarez Machain - 1990, MS177.004.001.027.00013 (Box 27)
    - Alvarez Machain [briefs and notes], 1990 -- 1991; MS177.004.001.027.00014 (Box 27)
    - Americas Watch - 9th Circuit brief (amicus curiae), 1990 -- 1991; MS177.004.001.027.00015 (Box 27)
    - Alvarez Machain bail motion - denial, 1990 -- 1991; MS177.004.001.027.00016 (Box 27)
    - [Motions], 1991; MS177.004.001.027.00017 (Box 27)
    - 9th Circuit decision in Alvarez Machain, 1991; MS177.004.001.027.00018 (Box 27)
    - Alvarez Machain: other amicus briefs to Supreme Court, 1991; MS177.004.001.027.00019 (Box 27)
    - Alvarez Machain briefs on appeal to 9th Circuit [1 of 2], 1991; MS177.004.001.027.00020 (Box 27)
    - Alvarez Machain briefs on appeal to 9th Circuit [2 of 2], 1991; MS177.004.001.028.00001 (Box 28)
    - [Permanent Council of the Organization of American States, Inter-American Juridical Committee opinion regarding US Supreme Court decision], 1992; MS177.004.001.028.00002 (Box 28)
    - World Policy Journal article, 1992; MS177.004.001.028.00003 (Box 28)
    - Machain / Zuno / Camarena clippings [1 of 2], 1992; MS177.004.001.028.00004 (Box 28)
    - Machain / Zuno / Camarena clippings [2 of 2], 1992; MS177.004.001.028.00005 (Box 28)
    - Alvarez Machain - civil suit, 1994 -- 1995; MS177.004.001.028.00006 (Box 28)
    - Alvarez Machain [1 of 4], 1991 -- 1992; MS177.004.001.028.00007 (Box 28)
    - Alvarez Machain [2 of 4], 2003; MS177.004.001.028.00008 (Box 28)
    - Alvarez Machain [3 of 4], 2003 -- 2004; MS177.004.001.028.00009 (Box 28)
    - Alvarez Machain [4 of 4], 2003 -- 2004; MS177.004.001.028.00010 (Box 28)
  - Ferdinand Marcos, 1962 -- 2004; 1986 -- 1999; MS177.004.002; 13.2 Linear Feet
    This series is arranged in rough chronological order.
    - Sison case in Philippines courts, 1981; MS177.004.002.028.00011 (Box 28)
    - [Sison] complaint, 1986; MS177.004.002.028.00012 (Box 28)
    - [Sison / Piopongco pleadings and proceedings before US District Court, 1 of 3], 1986; MS177.004.002.028.00013 (Box 28)
    - [Sison / Piopongco pleadings and proceedings before US District Court, 2 of 3], 1986; MS177.004.002.028.00014 (Box 28)
    - [Sison / Piopongco pleadings and proceedings before US District Court, 3 of 3], 1986; MS177.004.002.028.00015 (Box 28)
    - New York Land Co. v. Republic of Philippines, 1986; MS177.004.002.028.00016 (Box 28)
    - [Sison / Piopongco, 9th Circuit appeal, excerpt of record], 1986 -- 1987; MS177.004.002.028.00017 (Box 28)
    - [Sison / Piopongco, 9th Circuit appeal, appellants brief], 1987; MS177.004.002.028.00018 (Box 28)
    - [Piopongco complaint], 1987; MS177.004.002.028.00019 (Box 28)
    - [Trajano, 9th Circuit appeal, brief], 1987; MS177.004.002.028.00020 (Box 28)
    - [Hilao / Trajano, 9th Circuit appeal, reply brief], 1987; MS177.004.002.028.00021 (Box 28)
    - Republic of Philiippines v. Marcos - Kozinski opinion, review en banc, 1987; MS177.004.002.029.00001 (Box 29)
    - Philippines v. Marcos, 1987; MS177.004.002.029.00002 (Box 29)
    - [Sison response brief to US amicus curiae], 1987; MS177.004.002.029.00003 (Box 29)
    - Belli brief in opposition to government amicus curiae brief, 1987; MS177.004.002.029.00004 (Box 29)
    - Hilao / Trajano briefs of appeal, 1987; MS177.004.002.029.00005 (Box 29)
    - Sison v. Marcos - Sison appellants brief in reply to US government, 1987; MS177.004.002.029.00006 (Box 29)
    - Republic of Philippines v. Marcos, 9th Circuit, 1987; MS177.004.002.029.00007 (Box 29)
    - Sison v. Marcos, ACLU, V-1 volume 2.3.1, Ellen Lutz workfile, correspondence clip #1, 1987; MS177.004.002.029.00008 (Box 29)
    - Sison v. Marcos, ACLU, V-1 volume 2.3.1, Ellen Lutz workfile, court file clip #1, 1987; MS177.004.002.029.00009 (Box 29)
    - Sison v. Marcos, ACLU, V-1 volume 2.3.2, Ellen Lutz workfile, office memoranda and longhand notes, 1987 -- 1988; MS177.004.002.029.00010 (Box 29)
    - Sison v. Marcos, ACLU, V-1 volume 2.3.2, Ellen Lutz workfile, copies and duplicates, 1987; MS177.004.002.029.00011 (Box 29)
    - Amicus briefs - Sison v. Marcos on appeal, 1987 -- 1988; MS177.004.002.029.00012 (Box 29)
    - Sison v. Marcos - Law professors reply to US government brief, 1987 -- 1988; MS177.004.002.029.00013 (Box 29)
    - [Philippines v. Marcos, 9th Circuit, Judge Noonan opinion], 1988; MS177.004.002.029.00014 (Box 29)
    - US District Court (SDNY) indictment, Ferdinand and Imelda Marcos, 1988; MS177.004.002.029.00015 (Box 29)
    - Cultural Aspects in the Rehab of Torture Victims with Reference to Philippine Experience, June C P Lopez, MD, 1988; MS177.004.002.029.00016 (Box 29)